Guide to the Parents@Duke Records, 2002-2015 UA.28.01.0013
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Parents@Duke Records
2002-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Parents@Duke
UA.28.01.0013
0.5 Linear Feet
Parents@Duke was created in 2002 by members of the faculty and staff to advocate for improved policies and work culture for people with family responsibilities. The collection includes meeting notes, reports, correspondence, research, flyers, and other materials related to the activities of Parents@Duke.
Biographical / Historical
Parents@Duke was created in 2002 by members of the faculty and staff of Duke University to advocate for improved policies and work culture for people with family responsibilities. The group advocated for expanded parental leave for all employees, affordable child care, support for elder care, an increased number and improved quality of lactation rooms on campus, and other issues, meeting with President Nannerl Keohane and other administrators. The group sponsored event such as lectures and events to discuss improving policies around family responsibilities, conducted a survey of parents, and submitted reports to President Keohane. The group worked with the Women's Initiative in 2003 and 2004 to give most faculty and staff some paid parental leave.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Parents@Duke Records were received by the Duke University Archives as a gift in 2017.
Related Materials
Women's Network Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Collection Overview
The collection includes meeting notes, reports, correspondence, research, flyers, and other materials related to the activities of Parents@Duke. The materials document goal-setting discussions and advocacy efforts of the group with University administration as well as events and outreach.
Parenting -- United States; Parental leave; Working mothers -- North Carolina; Parents@Duke; Keohane, Nannerl O., 1940-; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University -- Staff
- Working Proposal for Improving Parents@Duke, undated (Box 1)
- Meeting Notes, 2002-2015 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 2002-2012 (Box 1)
- Articles/research, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
- Resources for Parents, 2002-2014 (Box 1)
- Parents@Duke reports, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
- Allies around campus, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
- Events, 2004-2005 (Box 1)
- Flyers and cards, undated (Box 1)
- Printed material, 2004 (Box 1)